<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Guitarist</string>
    <string name="basic_tasks">"You're now ready to take on some challenges!

These will determine whether or not you’ve mastered all the basic skills of playing the guitar. The following tunes have been carefully selected to put your strumming, note picking, clarity, playing comfort, chord variety, chord switching, consistency and endurance to the test:

•	All Along The Watchtower by Dave Matthews (opening bassline)
•	Come As You Are by Nirvana (opening tune)
•	Save Tonight by Eagle Eye Cherry (intro)
•	Wonderwall by Oasis (complete song)
•	Message In A Bottle by The Police (opening tune)
•	Sweet Child O’ Mine by Guns N Roses (opening tune)
•	New Slang by The Shins (complete song)
•	With or Without You by U2 (opening bassline and chords)


In order to learn how to play them, you will need to learn how to read guitar tablature, commonly known as ‘tabs’. Furthermore, it is up to you then look up the tabs for these tunes online. This is very simple, for example: you just need to Google search “All Along The Watchtower Dave Matthews bassline tab” and you will find a whole host of links directing you to your desired tabs. I would advise looking for guitar tabs on the website ‘Songsterr’ as it gives for all the other instruments at play as well in guitar form.

Once you’ve looked up the tabs, play the original audio mp3 on your favorite music streaming service such as Spotify or Youtube and get familiar with the sound. Pause the music, read the tabs and try to play them out on your own, slowly. Memorize the tune by playing it over and over again and then pick up the pace to the original song’s tempo. Then play the tune along with the song with perfect clarity, consistency and without feeling fatigue in your hand.

Once have managed to this for all the tasks listed above, you are ready to proceed to the ‘Intermediate’ category of this app. You are already equipped to play easy songs on your own and with your friends, however, it is highly recommended to learn the intermediate and advanced techniques so that it adds to your completeness as a guitarist and opens up your potential to play all of your favorite songs no matter how tricky you may have thought they were at first!"
    </string>
</resources>